# Sean Christopher Doyle

10-2044 Bluefields Drive, Burlington, ON. L7P 1K1

Cell Phone – (226) 820-2099

sean.chris.doyle@gmail.com

### **Executive Summary:**

I am a results-oriented software engineer with a background in Business Systems development and Geographic Information Systems and a passion for continuous learning.

Experienced in Front-End Web Development using JavaScript (including React and Vue) and building REST API's using Flask RESTful, ExpressJS and Object-relational mapping. Proficient using Relational Database Management Systems (SQL Server & PostgreSQL) and in data manipulation using ETL Tools such as SQL Server Integration Services.

With the ability to be a self-starter and build projects from the ground up, I also possess excellent interpersonal and communication skills. Collaborative by nature, I am able to take the needs and abilities of others into consideration while continuing to adhere to project deadlines.

#### **EDUCATION**

Centre of Geographic Sciences – Lawrencetown, Nova Scotia

Sep 2017 - Apr 2019

Diploma – Geographic Sciences

University of Guelph - Guelph, Ontario

Sep 2013 – Apr 2016

Bachelor of Arts – Geography Concentration

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Software Developer – Full-time

Jul 2019 - Present

International Financial Data Services / SS&C

- Developed a time tracking system using React and ExpressJS to replace existing licenced software
- Developed an On Call tracking module with approval workflows for days booked to integrate with previously developed time tracking system
- Led a project to develop a site for internal systems including new hire onboarding and Client management using React and ExpressJS
- Supervised a co-op student, managing sprint planning across multiple projects
- Developed REST API's using Spring Boot and Spring Data JPA as part of a more modern and scalable TA Services Infrastructure
- Configured Apache NiFi to ingest multiple file types and output to an Apache Kafka Consumer

- Developed and maintained C# and JavaScript SharePoint solutions based on user/client requirements
- Participated in bi-weekly agile sprints tracking progress using JIRA

## IT ADMINISTRATOR AND SUPPORT - Full-time

Jan 2017 - Mar 2017

## <u>Pinnacle IP Solutions</u>

- Assisted with organization of product and installation coordination
- Tasked with the creation of documentation to be presented to franchisees
- Managed an inventory spreadsheet to allow for efficient tracking of where inventory was used and what was in stock.

## **TURF STAFF – Full-time (summer)**

Mill Run Golf Course

Jun 2016 - Jun 2019

- Successfully completed time-sensitive duties requiring a high attention to detail
- Daily interaction with coworkers as well as management
- Tasked with projects given minimal supervision

### **SKILLS**

Languages:	Database:
<ul> <li>JavaScript</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Microsoft SQL Server</li> </ul>
o Java	<ul> <li>PostgreSQL</li> </ul>
o C#	o PostGIS
o Python	GIS:
Web Development:	<ul> <li>ArcGIS Desktop</li> </ul>
o HTML	o ArcGIS Pro
o CSS	o QGIS
o React	GIS - Web Development Libraries:
o Vue	o Leaflet
o Express	<ul> <li>OpenLayers</li> </ul>
<ul> <li>Flask-RESTful</li> </ul>	o Mapbox
o Jest	
Object-relational Mapping:	
o Django	
o SQLAlchemy	

### **OTHER PROJECTS**

## **Forest Fragmentation Metrics Script**

With guidance from the faculty at the Centre of Geographic Sciences, I created a Python script tool for ArcGIS Pro to measure the validity of perceived widespread forest clear cutting in western Nova Scotia. The tool creates a file containing forestry metrics.

- Used Python to create an ArcGIS Pro script tool to output a user defined CSV file containing forest fragmentation metrics
- Utilized multiple Python packages such as ArcPy, NumPy, Pandas and PyShp to output created shapefiles in GeoJSON format
- Users enter the locations of an input shapefile, scratch folder location, and output file name and folder location
- Input data used was sourced from the Department of Lands and Forestry Nova Scotia and Open Data Nova Scotia

#### **Annapolis Valley Trails Coalition Data Migration**

The objective of this project was to create a central database to manage trail data on behalf of the Annapolis Valley Trails Coalition. The Coalition manages a network of trails covering Grand Pre to Annapolis Royal, Nova Scotia. The prior system for managing spatial and non-spatial trail data consisted of a combination of CSV files and paper inspection forms. To create a system that is both scalable and more robust than the current system, a PostgreSQL database was created. Through consultation with the client, a database schema was created and existing CSV files were imported into the database wherever possible.

- Client-based school project working in a team of three
- Migrated trail, bridge, culvert and signage information from paper / CSV format to PostgreSQL database format
- Geographic information added to database tables using existing coordinate fields and PostGIS SQL commands